Guide to the Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Manuscripts, 1828-1960; Series II; 13.35; (34 boxes)
  - Manuscripts by Others
    - Henley, William Ernest
      - "Ballade R.L.S." (7243), 1882 February 22 (Box 50, Folder 1085)
      - ["The blackbird sang, the skies were glad & clean..."] (7244), 1875 May 7 (Box 50, Folder 1086)
      - "I. M. Charles Baxter" (7245), undated (Box 50, Folder 1087)
      - [I. M. R. G. C. B.] (7246), [1878] (Box 50, Folder 1088)
      - "New Books" (7247), undated (Box 50, Folder 1089)
      - ["Spring winds that blow..."] (7248), undated (Box 50, Folder 1090)
      - [To M. E. H.] (7249), undated (Box 50, Folder 1091)
      - ["To ponder leave my fancies free..."] (7250), undated (Box 50, Folder 1092)
      - ["A world of leafage murmurous & a-twinkle..."] (7251), 1900 June (Box 50, Folder 1093)
    - Hills, Gertrude
      - "A Catalogue of the Saville Club Gift..." (7252), undated (Box 50, Folder 1094)
    - Honolulu Scottish Thistle Club
      - [Resolution on the Death of R.L.S.] (7253), 1894 December 14
    - [Hutchison, Thomas C.?]
      - "R.L.S." (7254), undated (Box 50, Folder 1095)
    - Jessop, G[eorge] H[enry]
      - "Kidnapped: A Play in Five Acts Founded on "The Adventures of David Balfour""(7255), undated (Box 50, Folder 1096)
    - John Lane Company
      - [Agreement] (7258), 1895 June 20 (Box 51, Folder 1097)
    - Kahn, Edgar M.
      - "Some Aspects of Robert Louis Stevenson" (7256), 1955 February 7 (Box 51, Folder 1098)
    - Kelland, Philip
      - [Certificate of R.L.S.'s Creditable Work...] (7257), 1869 April 9 (Box 51, Folder 1099)
    - Lane, John
    - Lang, Andrew
      - ["He who sleeps on the Vaea crest..."] (7259)
      - "To R.L.S." (7260), undated (Box 51, Folder 1100)
    - Le Gallienne, Richard
      - "Robert Louis Stevenson: An Elegy" (7261), [circa 1894] (Box 51, Folder 1101)
    - McCollum, van Buren
      - "Sail, Ho! Ahoy! Casco" (7265)
    - McLaren, Charles Benjamin Bright
      - "Law Notes" (7266), [1870-1871] (Box 51, Folder 1102)
    - Milner, E. V.
      - "Robert Louis Stevenson" (7267), 1950 November 15 (Box 51, Folder 1103)
    - Minto, R. M.
      - "Invocation at the Robert Louis Stevenson Commemoration..." (8372), 1956 November 13 (Box 51, Folder 1104)
    - Mitchell & Baxter
      - "Accounts Current Between Robert Louis Stevenson..." (7268), 1877-1898 (Box 51, Folder 1105)
      - "Note of Entries in Mitchell & Baxter's Cash Ledgers..." (7269), 1884-1885 (Box 51, Folder 1106)
      - [Wills of R.L.S. Questions Concerning] (7270), [1893?] (Box 51, Folder 1107)
    - Myers, Frederic William Henry
      - "Notes on Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde" (7271-7272), 1886 (Box 51, Folder 1108)
    - Nash, H. D.
      - "Stevenson's "Fables"" (7273), undated (Box 51, Folder 1109)
    - Osbourne, Mrs. Charles Glidden
    - Osbourne, Katharine Durham
      - "Dumyat," note (7275), undated (Box 51, Folder 1110)
      - [The Marriage of Robert Louis Stevenson], announcement (7276), undated (Box 51, Folder 1111)
      - "Some Aspects of Robert Louis Stevenson" (7277), undated (Box 51, Folder 1112)
    - Osbourne, Lloyd
      - [Diary] (7278), 1889 (Box 51, Folder 1113)
      - [Statement Concerning the R. L. Stevenson Trust Funds], undated (Box 51, Folder 1114)
      - "Treasure Island," play (7279), 1902 June 18 (Box 52, Folder 1115)
    - Osbourne, May Peabody
      - [Extract From Will] (7274), 1935 June 3 (Box 52, Folder 1116)
    - Purdy, Helen Throop
      - "R.L.S.--Another Side" (7280), undated (Box 52, Folder 1117)
    - [Samoa. Supreme Court]
      - Court grants (7281-7282), 1896-1897 (Box 52, Folder 1118-1119)
    - Savile Club
      - [Proposer and Supporters of R.L.S. as a Member...] (7283), 1874 (Box 52, Folder 1120)
    - Stevenson, Fanny Van de Grift
      - The Bottle Imp, notes (7286), undated (Box 52, Folder 1121)
      - [Cookery Recipes] (7287), undated (Box 52, Folder 1122-1123)
      - [Incidents In the Life of R.L.S....] (7288), undated (Box 52, Folder 1124)
      - [Knitting], notes (7289), undated (Box 52, Folder 1125)
      - [Less Than Kith and More Than Kind], scenario (7290), undated (Box 52, Folder 1126)
      - [Music], notes (7291), undated (Box 52, Folder 1127)
      - ["'Neath the waving palm tree branches..."] (7292), undated (Box 52, Folder 1128)
      - [Notes Concerning John Miller...] (7293), undated (Box 52, Folder 1129)
      - [Notes of Experiences in Australia] (7294), 1893 March 12 (Box 52, Folder 1130)
      - [Orders] (7295 and 8376), 1892, 1897 (Box 52, Folder 1131-1132)
      - ["Please pin this up in a prominent place..."] (7296), undated (Box 52, Folder 1133)
      - "Ramblings of a Housewife" (7297), undated (Box 52, Folder 1134)
      - Records of Family Faculties (7298), 1884, undated (Box 52, Folder 1135)
      - [Lord Lorimer] (7299), undated (Box 52, Folder 1136)
      - [Stains. Removal], notes (7300), undated (Box 52, Folder 1137)
      - [Vanumanutagi] material (7301), 1893 (Box 52, Folder 1138)
      - [Will] (7302)
      - [Will] (7303), 1912 November 2 (Box 52, Folder 1139)
    - Stevenson, M. I. (Margaret Isabella) (mother)
      - "Baby's Record" (8377), 1850-1858 (Box 52, Folder 1140)
      - Diaries (7304), 1853-1872 (Box 53, Folder 1141-1160)
      - Diaries (7304), 1874-1889 (Box 54, Folder 1161-1178)
      - Diaries (7304), 1890-1897 (Box 55, Folder 1179-1187)
      - "Extracts From Jewish Prayer Book" (7305)
      - [Minutes of Meetings of the Ladies Committee...] (7306)
      - [Miscellaneous Papers] (7307), undated (Box 56, Folder 1188)
      - [Stevenson Family], genealogy (7309), 1895 March 4 (Box 56, Folder 1189)
    - Stevenson, Robert
      - Diary (8378), 1820 (Box 56, Folder 1190)
      - [Stevenson Family], genealogy (7310), undated (Box 56, Folder 1191)
    - Stevenson, Robert Alan Mowbray
      - ["Stray leaves and winds in autumn..."] (7311), undated (Box 56, Folder 1192)
      - "Whistler" (7312), undated (Box 56, Folder 1193)
    - Stevenson, Robert Wilson
      - "The Old and the New" (7313), undated (Box 56, Folder 1194-1195)
    - Stevenson, Thomas
      - "Mr. T. Stevenson's Azimuthal Condensing System..." (7315), undated (Box 56, Folder 1196)
      - "Brief of Evidence in Manchester Canal Scheme" (7317), 1885 (Box 56, Folder 1197)
      - "Coloured Distinctions For Lighthouses" (7320), 1868 January 24 (Box 56, Folder 1198)
      - ["Description of proposed automatic guage [sic]..."] (7321)
      - Diary (7322), 1841 (Box 56, Folder 1199)
      - "Ecclesiastica" (7323), undated (Box 56, Folder 1200)
      - "First Designs for Condensing Lights" (7326), undated (Box 56, Folder 1201)
      - [Holophotal System of Illuminatng Lighthouses] (7327-7328), undated (Box 56, Folder 1202-1203)
      - [Improvements Adopted in Optical Apparatus] (7329), undated (Box 56, Folder 1204)
      - [Label for a Picture...] (7331), 1856 April (Box 56, Folder 1205)
      - [The Life of Man] (7332), undated (Box 56, Folder 1206)
      - [Lighthouse Illumination], fragment (8385), undated (Box 56, Folder 1207)
      - [Lighting] (7334-7336), undated (Box 56, Folder 1208-1210)
      - [Lists] (7337-7338), [circa 1877] (Box 56, Folder 1211)
      - "Mode of Masking or Cutting off Sharply the Light..." (7341), undated (Box 56, Folder 1212)
      - "Nesti Errors Which Have Crept in...Previous Publications" (7342), undated (Box 56, Folder 1213)
      - "Night Spectacles for Use at Sea" (7343-7344), 1879, undated (Box 56, Folder 1214)
      - [Notebooks]
        - [71], undated (Box 56, Folder 1215)
          "Notes on Miscellaneous Subjects" (7318)
          "Notes on Chemistry" (7319)
          "Essays on the Metals Chiefly Used in the Arts" (7324)
        - [72], undated (Box 56, Folder 1216)
          "Admiralty Sailing Directions" (7314)
          "Books in Box" (7316)
          "Fidelity of Highlanders" (7325)
          [A Jetty and its Effect on a River Bank] (7330)
          [Mathematical Notes] (7339)
          [Union Between England and Scotland, 1707], notes (7354)
          [John Walker Essays...], notes (7356)
        - "73", undated (Box 56, Folder 1217)
          "Extracts From Jewish Prayer Book" (7305)
          "Lighthouse Illumination" (7333)
          [Mathematical Notes] (7340)
      - "Notice of a Proposed Symbolic Representation of the Physical..." (7345), undated (Box 56, Folder 1218)
      - [Observation of Smoke to Determine Wind Velocities] (7346), undated (Box 56, Folder 1219)
      - "Ofiice Book" (8379), 1836 (Box 57, Folder 1220)
      - "On the Family of Purves" (7347-7348), 1873, undated (Box 57, Folder 1221)
      - "On the Vertical Distribution of the Light from Lighthouses..." (7844), 1878 November 7 (Box 57, Folder 1222)
      - ["Optical arrangement for investigating invisible portions..."] (7349)
      - ["The parabolic arcs have a common..."] (7350), undated (Box 57, Folder 1223)
      - "Professor Tait's Formula for Wind Observations" (7353), undated (Box 57, Folder 1224)
      - [Storms] (7351), undated (Box 57, Folder 1225)
      - "The Superiority of the Azimuthal Condensing System..." (7352), [circa 1881] (Box 57, Folder 1226)
      - "The Voluntary Principle of Religious Equality..." (7354), undated (Box 57, Folder 1227)
    - Stevenson House
      - "Master List: The Robert Louis Stevenson Collections" (7357), 1960 March 22 (Box 57, Folder 1228)
      - "Index for Scrapbooks II to VI of Stevenson's Mother" (7358), [circa 1960] (Box 57, Folder 1229)
    - Stone, Arthur F.
      - ["From a Biography of General H.C. Ide..."] (7359)
    - Strong, Austin
      - "French Book" (7360), 1894 May (Box 57, Folder 1230)
      - "Golf Fish" (7361), undated (Box 57, Folder 1231)
      - "Adelaide Boodle" (7362), undated (Box 57, Folder 1232)
      - "Note of Vailima Life" (8390), undated (Box 57, Folder 1233)
      - "South Sea Holidays at Vau-Vau" (7363), undated (Box 58, Folder 1234)
      - [A Trip from Wellington, N.Z. to Vailima, 1897] (7364-7365) (Box 58, Folder 1235-1236)
      - [A Trip to Aukland, N.Z.] (7366), undated (Box 58, Folder 1237)
      - "A Tropical Robin Hood" (7367), undated (Box 58, Folder 1238)
      - "Van de Veur" (7368), n.y. October 25 (Box 58, Folder 1239)
    - Strong, Isobel
    - Taine, Hippolyte
      - Histoire de la littérature anglaise (volumes 12 and 14), printed version, annotated by Robert Louis Stevenson (7927), 1882 (Box 58, Folder 1240)
    - Trood, Thomas
      - [Tract of Land Containing Graves...] (7373), 1896 April 30
    - Union House
      - [Register] (7374), 1887-1888
    - Watt, Lauchlan, MacLean
      - "R.L.S." (8392), 1925 August 6 (Box 58, Folder 1241)
    - The Wilt's & Dorset Banking Company Limited
      - Bank book (7375), 1885-1887 (Box 58, Folder 1242)
    - Unidentified
      - Balfour family genealogy (7376), undated (Box 58, Folder 1243)
      - [Condolence on the Death of R.L.S.] (7377), [1894?] (Box 58, Folder 1244)
      - [Curaçao] (7378), undated (Box 58, Folder 1245)
      - [Dirge Sung on the Death of R.L.S.] (7379-7380), 1894 (Box 58, Folder 1246)
      - "The Legend of the Great Drought on the Island of Maui" (7381), undated (Box 58, Folder 1247)
      - "Hawaii Version of the Legend of Hua" (7382), undated (Box 58, Folder 1248)
      - Menu (7383), 1891 August 20 (Box 58, Folder 1249)
      - "Packing Particulars of Cases of Furnishings" (7384), [circa 1883] (Box 58, Folder 1250)
      - 'Transcript of Papers on Charles Edward Stuart..." (7385), 1894 November 8 (Box 58, Folder 1251)
      - ["State of stocks and realized funds..."] (7386), undated (Box 58, Folder 1252)
      - ["Much of his private charity was unknown..."] (7387), undated (Box 58, Folder 1253)
      - "Memorandum for Mr. R. Louis Stevenson in regard to the effect..."] (7388), [1887?] (Box 58, Folder 1254)
      - "Chronological Statement of the Income from the Trust Funds of the Late Thomas Stevenson" (7389), 1894 November (Box 58, Folder 1255)
      - "List of Sympathizers in Proposed Memorial to the Late Robert Louis Stevenson" (7390), [1894?] (Box 58, Folder 1256)
      - [Tailor's Account With R.L.S.] (7391), 1891-1894
      - "Autographs" (7392), 1890-1910 (Box 58, Folder 1257)
        Includes notes by Robert Louis Stevenson
- Additions and Other Materials, 1876-1966; Series III; 5.21; (13 boxes)
  Series III. Additions and Other Materials is organized into six subseries: Correspondence, Writings, Photographs and Graphic Material, Artwork and Objects, Memorabilia, and Other Materials.
  Series III consists almost entirely of Stevenson related materials not documented in McKay's A Stevenson Library: Catalogue. This includes the photographs, artwork, and memorabilia that came to the library in the early 1950s with the principal gifts of Edwin J. Beinecke's collection, as well as smaller gifts and purchases made through the 1960s--Mr. Beinecke supported the collection until his death in 1970. In the first case, materials appear to have been omitted from the Catalogue; some items are even accompanied by notes, "Not Cataloged" or "No RLS Interest," made, presumably, by McKay in the course of cataloging. In the latter case, some acquisitions post-date the compilation of the final volume of the Catalogue (1964).
  During processing some materials previously classified as MS Vault Stevenson "Supplemental" were traced to sources other than Mr. Beinecke. These materials were removed to the Robert Louis Stevenson Collection (GEN MSS ?).
  Correspondence contains letters to and from Stevenson, including transcriptions of letters from J. M. Barrie, William Ernest Henley, Will Hicok Low, and others. Purchases are often accompanied by vendor correspondence and/or descriptions. O ther corrrespondence consists of third-party letters between family, friends, and others also represented in Series I. Correspondence.
  Writings consists of a small number of works by Stevenson and others, chiefly printed versions.
  The series features original photographs and artwork relating to Stevenson. Photographs and Graphic Material includes photographic prints and printed reproductions, including postcards and clippings. Materials are subdivided for images of People, Robert Louis Stevenson in Artwork, Places, and Other. There are photographs of Stevenson, family, and friends, many Stevenson homes and residences, and the areas in which he lived and travelled, as well as albums containing material relating chiefly to Stevenson's life in Samoa. Additional photographs and printed reproductions can be found in the scrapbooks.
  Artistic representations of Stevenson include work by well-known artists working around the turn of the 20th century. Works include: oil and watercolor portraits by Girolamo Nerli and Percy F. S. Spence respectively; charcoal portraits by Nerli and John Singer Sargent; busts and reliefs by Gutzon Borglum, Allen Hutchinson, and Augustus Saint-Gaudens; and engravings, etchings, and woodcut and linoleum prints by artists Robert Bryden, Timothy Cole, Samuel Hollyer, Thomas Johnson, Joseph Simpson, and Samuel Johnson Woolf. In addition, there are numerous original drawings and watercolors for book illustrations by Robert Browne, William Hole, George Varian, and R. Canton Woodville, as well as original drawings by James Renwick Brevoort and Erastus Salisbury Field.
  Memorabilia consists of numerous objects, such as Stevenson's chess set and pipe, and Other Materials features scrapbooks containing clippings, printed ephemera, and original artwork and photographs.
  - Correspondence
    Correspondence is arranged into five subseries: Robert Louis Stevenson Correspondence, Fanny Van de Grift Correspondence, Luther J. B. Correspondence, Austin Strong Correspondence, and Other Third Party Correspondence.
    - Robert Louis Stevenson Correspondence
      - Adam and Charles Black (Firm), 1876 March 20 (Box 59, Folder 1258)
      - Bain, James, n.y. October 6 (Box 59, Folder 1259)
      - Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew) (copies), 1892-1895 (Box 59, Folder 1260)
      - [Brandt], "Doctor", 1885 January 4 (Box 59, Folder 1261)
      - [Crockett, S. R.?], [circa 1888] (Box 59, Folder 1262)
      - Crosby, Miss E. R., 1872-1874 (Box 59, Folder 1263)
      - Haggard, Rider (copies), [circa 1892], undated (Box 59, Folder 1264)
      - Henderson, [James], undated (Box 59, Folder 1265)
      - Henley, William Ernest (copies), 1876-1887, undated (Box 59, Folder 1266-1268)
      - Jersey, Margaret Elizabeth Leigh Child-Villiers, Countess of, [circa 1892] (Box 59, Folder 1269)
      - [Lapoukine?], Olga, 1886 (Box 59, Folder 1270)
      - Low, Will Hicok (copies), 1883-1893 (Box 59, Folder 1271-1273)
      - Malietoa, King of Samoa, 1894 (Box 59, Folder 1274)
      - Mataafa, F. M., 1892 (Box 59, Folder 1275)
      - Monkhouse, W. Cosmo (William Cosmo), 1884 April (Box 59, Folder 1276)
      - Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain), n.y. May 1 (Box 59, Folder 1277)
      - [Samoa Political Letters] (copies), 1894, undated (Box 59, Folder 1278-1279)
      - Smith, Elder & Co., 1887 June 7 (Box 59, Folder 1280)
      - "Sosima", [1892] (Box 59, Folder 1281)
      - Speculative Society [of Edinburgh?], 1892 July 20 (Box 59, Folder 1282)
      - Stevenson, Robert, Alan Mowbray (copies), 1865-1893, undated (Box 59, Folder 1283-1287)
      - Stevenson, Thomas (copies), 1854, 1856 (Box 59, Folder 1288)
      - [Taylor], Ida, undated (Box 59, Folder 1289)
      - Unidentified, 1894, undated (Box 59, Folder 1290)
      - Empty envelopes, 1881-1892 (Box 59, Folder 1291)
      - "Transcripts and facsimiles of letters...", 1894-1923, undated (Box 60, Folder 1292-1296)
        Includes copies of third-party correspondence
    - Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson Correspondence
      - Balfour & Co., 1893 November 9 (Box 60, Folder 1297)
      - Cunningham, Alison, [1895-1912] (Box 60, Folder 1298)
      - Field, Isobel, 1896, 1906 (Box 60, Folder 1299)
      - Fussell, Josie, 1908 November (Box 60, Folder 1300)
      - Haggard, Bazett M[ichael], 1897 March 19 (Box 60, Folder 1301)
      - Lavigne, M. R., 1904 March 27 (Box 60, Folder 1302)
      - [Mattos, Katharine de], undated (Box 60, Folder 1303)
      - Meredith, William M[axse], 1910 December 28 (Box 60, Folder 1304)
      - Murdoch, M., 1910 April 27 (Box 60, Folder 1305)
      - Stoddard, Charles Warren, 1903 June (Box 60, Folder 1306)
      - Others, 1887, undated (Box 60, Folder 1307)
    - Luther J. B. Lincoln Correspondence
      - Cable, [George Washington?], 1894 November 7 (Box 60, Folder 1308)
      - Chadwick, John W[hite?], 1895 December 11 (Box 60, Folder 1309)
      - Clarke, "Miss" [Ellen?], undated (Box 60, Folder 1310)
      - Conway, Moncure Daniel, 1894 November 20 (Box 60, Folder 1311)
      - Harrison, C. C., n.y. December 4 (Box 60, Folder 1312)
      - Lang, Andrew, 1895 April 4 (Box 60, Folder 1313)
      - Lathrop, G[eorge] P[arsons], 1895 February 19 (Box 60, Folder 1314)
      - [Parker?], Gilbert, 1893 November 25 (Box 60, Folder 1315)
      - Stuart, Ruth McEnery, undated (Box 60, Folder 1316)
      - Van Dyke, Henry, 1894 November 30 (Box 60, Folder 1317)
      - Warner, Charles Dudley, 1895 December 8 (Box 60, Folder 1318)
      - Wiggin, Kate Douglas Smith, undated (Box 60, Folder 1319)
      - Others, 1894-1895, undated (Box 60, Folder 1320)
    - Austin Strong Correspondence
      - Balfour, Graham, Sir, 1907-1927 (Box 60, Folder 1321)
      - Balfour, Jane Whyte, 1901-1907 (Box 60, Folder 1322)
      - Balfour, Rhoda, 1907-1939 (Box 60, Folder 1323)
      - Belasco, David, 1909, undated (Box 60, Folder 1324)
      - Boodle, Adelaide, 1907-[1932?], undated (Box 61, Folder 1325-1326)
      - Chevalier, Albert, 1908 (Box 61, Folder 1327)
      - Colvin, Frances, 1916, undated (Box 61, Folder 1328)
      - Colvin, Sidney, 1907-1919 (Box 61, Folder 1329)
      - Davies, Hubert Henry, 1905-1907, undated (Box 61, Folder 1330)
      - Field, Isobel, 1945-1951, undated (Box 61, Folder 1331)
      - Fitch, Clyde, 1908, undated (Box 61, Folder 1332)
      - French, Herbert, 1910 May 6 (Box 61, Folder 1333)
      - Frohman, Charles, 1907, undated (Box 61, Folder 1334)
      - Galsworthty, Ida, 1911-1912, undated (Box 61, Folder 1335)
      - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1906 May 16 (Box 61, Folder 1336)
      - Gillette, William, 1917 March 14 (Box 61, Folder 1337)
      - Gosse, Edmund, 1907 April 26 (Box 61, Folder 1338)
      - Jenkin, Anne, undated (Box 61, Folder 1339)
      - Low, W. H[icok], 1908-1909 (Box 61, Folder 1340)
      - Mitchell, Langdon [Elwyn?], n.y. November 19 (Box 61, Folder 1341)
      - Pinero, Arthur Wing, Sir, 1911 September 24 (Box 61, Folder 1342)
      - Robert Louis Stevenson Club, [1951 March 19] (Box 61, Folder 1343)
      - Sheldon, Edward, undated (Box 61, Folder 1344)
      - Skinner, Otis, undated (Box 61, Folder 1345)
      - Stoddard, Charles Warren, 1900-1901 (Box 61, Folder 1346)
      - Tassin, Algernon de Vivier, 1908 December 2 (Box 61, Folder 1347)
      - Terry, Edward, 1910 May 12 (Box 61, Folder 1348)
      - Tree, Herbert Beerbohm, Sir, 1907 August 12 (Box 61, Folder 1349)
      - United States. President (1913-1921: Wilson), 1918 July 29 (Box 61, Folder 1350)
      - Walpole, Hugh, Sir, 1922 November 3 (Box 61, Folder 1351)
      - Warfield, David, 1907 November 25 (Box 61, Folder 1352)
      - Wilson, Francis, 1903-1909 (Box 61, Folder 1353)
      - [Wilson?], Maud (cousin), 1907 May 7 (Box 61, Folder 1354)
      - Yale University. Library, 1951, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 1355)
      - Others, 1901-1918, undated (Box 61, Folder 1356-1357)
    - Other Third Party Correspondence
      - Abbe, Robert to "Richard", 1905 June 12 (Box 61, Folder 1358)
      - Balfour, Graham to Sidney Colvin, 1925
      - Balfour, Jane Whyte to Alison Cunningham, 1888, 1897 (Box 61, Folder 1359)
      - Beinecke, Edwin J. (Edwin John) to George L. McKay, 1954 -1964 (Box 61, Folder 1360)
      - Beinecke, Edwin J. (Edwin John) to Yale University Library, 1965-1966 (Box 61, Folder 1361)
      - Bispham, David [Scull?] to Isobel Field, 1901 November 12 (Box 61, Folder 1362)
      - Clarke, Ellen to [Margaret Isabella] Stevenson, 1896-1897 (Box 61, Folder 1363)
      - Cunningham, Alison to Mrs. Ellery Holbrook, 1906 June 26 (Box 61, Folder 1364)
      - Cunningham, Alison to unidentified, undated (Box 61, Folder 1365)
      - Dewolf Hopper, Will to "Samuel", 1909 January 28 (Box 61, Folder 1366)
      - Farber-Robertson, [J.?] to unidentified, 1907 February (Box 61, Folder 1367)
      - [Farren], M. A. to H. J. Moors, 1916-1917 (Box 61, Folder 1368)
      - Field, Isobel to James Burton Pond, [1899]-1901 (Box 61, Folder 1369)
      - Franklin, Jean to Mr. Peabody, undated (Box 61, Folder 1370)
      - Gordon, [General] to unidentified, undated (Box 61, Folder 1371)
        Includes letter, dated 1950, to Austin Strong from United States Dept. of State
      - [Gordon, L. S.?], to [William Ernest] Henley, 1884 January 25 (Box 62, Folder 1372)
      - Gosse, Edmund with William Ernest Henley (copies), 1875-1895, undated (Box 62, Folder 1373)
      - Great Britain. Metropolitan Police Office to Longmans, Green & Co., 1885 May 1 (Box 62, Folder 1374)
      - Grover, Edwin O[sgood] to Edwin J. Beinecke, 1957 (Box 62, Folder 1375)
      - Hadow, W. H. [(William Henry)?] to Graham [Balfour?], 1896 January 7 (Box 62, Folder 1376)
      - Hartopp, [Lady] to [Ida] Taylor, [circa 1886] (Box 62, Folder 1377)
      - Hays, Helen H. to [Dora Norton] Williams, 1885 January 26 (Box 62, Folder 1378)
      - Henley, William Ernest to Charles Baxter, 1875-1894, undated (Box 62, Folder 1379-1384)
      - Henley, William Ernest to John Lane, 1892-1895 (Box 62, Folder 1385)
      - Henley, William Ernest to [Maccoll?], undated (Box 62, Folder 1386)
      - James, Henry to Isobel Field (copy), 1898 December 20 (Box 62, Folder 1387)